tescomobile.ie 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy | Tesco Mobile

At Tesco Mobile, we’re working hard to serve customer a little better every day. Looking after the personal data you share with us is a hugely important part of this. We want you to be confident that your data is safe and secure with us, and understand how we use it to offer you a better and more personalised shopping experience. 

## What this policy covers

The data controller is Tesco Mobile Ireland Limited (referred to in this policy as "we" or "us").

We are committed to doing the right thing when it comes to how we collect, use and protect your personal data. That's why we've developed this privacy and cookies policy ("Policy"), which: 

  * sets out the types of personal data that we collect;
  * explains how and why we collect and use your personal data;
  * explains when and why we will share personal data within the Tesco Group and with other organisations; and
  * explains the rights and choices you have when it comes to your personal data.

We offer a wide range of products and services, so we want you to be clear about what this Policy covers. This Policy applies to you if you use our services (referred to in this Policy as "our Services"). Using our Services means: 

  * contacting us in relation to our products and services
  * buying or using our products and services
  * engaging with us over the phone, or online, or otherwise using any of the websites ("our Websites") or Social Media channels, or mobile applications ("our Mobile Apps") where this Policy is posted; or
  * registering your Clubcard with us
  * subscribe to newsletters, alerts or other services from us;

This Policy also refers to our use of CCTV systems as managed and provided by Tesco Ireland Limited. Further details can be found in their privacy and cookie policy. 

Some other parts of our business and other Tesco Group companies may need to collect and use personal data to provide you with their products and services and for certain other purposes. They have their own privacy policies that explain how they use your personal data.

Our Websites or Mobile Apps may contain links to other websites operated by other organisations that have their own privacy policies. Please make sure you read the terms and conditions and privacy policy carefully before providing any personal data on a website as we do not accept any responsibility or liability for websites of other organisations.

## Personal data we collect

This section tells you what personal data we may collect from you when you use our Services and what other personal data we may receive from other sources.

When you register for our Services, you may provide us with: | 

  * Your personal details, including your postal and billing addresses, email addresses, phone numbers and date of birth and title
  * Unique device identifiers such IMEI, IMSI title, passwords, account number
  * Proof of address and identity (such as utility bill or photo id)
  * Payment information such as bank account, credit or debit card information
  * Employment details 
  * Marketing preference, National Directory Database contact preference, 
  * Some information defined as “Special Categories” of personal data for example if you have a vison or hearing impairment so that we can provide appropriate service to you in accordance with our regulatory obligations.
  * Register your Clubcard to avail of rewards

---|---  
When you use our mobile telecommunication services, we may collect or you may provide us with: | 

  * Traffic data such as calls, texts, MMS, data usage including details on date, time duration, costs, location. This data is processed in accordance with the Communications (Retention of Data) Act, 2011

When you shop with us online or browse our Websites or use our Mobile Apps, we may collect: | 

  * Information about your online purchases (for example, what you have bought, when and where you bought it and how you paid for it)
  * Information about your online browsing behaviour on our Websites and Mobile Apps and information about when you click on one of our adverts (including those shown on other organisations’ websites)
  * Information about any devices you have used to access our Services (including the make, model and operating system, IP address, browser type and mobile device identifiers)

When you use Clubcard to shop with us, or use Clubcard vouchers or coupons, we may collect: | 

  * Transaction information, including the in-store and online purchases you earn Clubcard points for and how you use your Clubcard coupons with Tesco Mobile

When you contact us or we contact you or you take part in promotions, competitions, surveys or reviews about our Services, we may collect: | 

  * Personal data you provide about yourself anytime you contact us about our Services (for example, your name, username and contact details), including by phone, email or post or when you speak with us through social media
  * Details of the emails and other digital communications we send to you that you open, including any links in them that you click on
  * Your feedback and contributions to customer surveys or reviews.

When you visit our locations in Tesco Ireland Limited stores | 

  * footage of you may be recorded on CCTV systems as provided by Tesco Ireland Limited

##  Other sources of personal data

We may also use personal data from other sources, such as other communications service providers and network operators, specialist companies that supply information, online media channels, our Retail Partners and public registers. For example, this other personal data helps us to: 

  * Facilitate mobile number switching, provide roaming services
  * Enable our decision making through credit scoring and or automated decision making systems when assessing an application
  * Protect our business from fraud or debt
  * Manage your Clubcard coupons with Tesco Mobile 
  * Review and improve the accuracy of the data we hold; and
  * Improve and measure the effectiveness of our marketing communications, including online advertising.

## How and why we use personal data

This section explains in detail how and why we use personal data. 

**We use personal data to** |  **This means that processing your personal data allows us to** |  **Why do we process your personal data in this way?** |  **Legal Basis**  
---|---|---|---  
  
**Make our Services available to you**

| 

Meet with our regulatory and legislative obligations such as processing and retaining traffic data i.e. calls, text, MMS, data usage, date, time, duration, costs, location

Identify validation, fraud prevention

| 

Meet our various obligations as a telecommunications provider as applicable from time to time such as Communications (Retention of Data) Act, 2011

| 

Legal Obligation  
  
Provide you with telecommunications services  
Provide billing for your use of our services  
Process payments for your use of our services  
Provide you with customer care

Update you on changes to your services

| 

We need to process your personal data so that we can manage your customer accounts, provide you with the goods and services you want to buy and help you with any orders and refunds you may ask for.

| 

Contractual Necessity  
\- provision of services  
\- purchase & transactions data  
\- contact details

We will not be able to provide you with your products or services if you do not provide us with this information.  
  
Manage our credit risk profile  |  Legitimate interests   
  
**Manage and improve our day-to-day operations**

| 

Manage and improve our Websites and Mobile Apps

| 

We use cookies and similar technologies on our Websites and Mobile Apps to improve your customer experience.

Some cookies are necessary so you should not disable these if you want to be able to use all the features of our Websites and Mobile Apps.  You can disable other cookies but this may affect your customer experience. For more information about cookies and how you can disable them, see the cookies and similar technologies section.

| 

Legitimate Interests  
  
Help to develop and improve our product range, services, stores, information technology systems, know-how and the way we communicate with you

| 

We rely on the use of personal data to carry out market research and internal research and development, and to improve our information technology systems (including security) and our product range, services and stores.  This allows us to serve you better as a customer.

| 

Legitimate Interest

Contractual Necessity   
  
Detect and prevent fraud or other crime

| 

It is important for us to monitor how our Services are used to detect and prevent fraud, other crimes and the misuse of services.  This helps us to make sure that you can safely use our Services.

| 

Legal Obligation

Contractual Necessity

Legitimate Interest  
  
Investigate and respond to complaints or illegal activity on our service or activity outside our terms and conditions

| 

To ensure that we are adequately investigating and addressing any complaints

| 

Legal Obligation

Contractual Necessity

Legitimate Interest  
  
So that we can investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities and violations of our Terms of Service and/or applicable law.

| 

To ensure that we are protecting our services from misuse

| 

Legal Obligation

Contractual Necessity

Legitimate Interest  
  
In many cases we aggregate and/or anonymise your personal information so that it no longer identifies you. 

We use this data so that we can better understand our customers and how they use our services so that we can improve our services to provide a better customer experience or to create new services

| 

Enhance our products and services

| 

Legitimate Interest  
  
**Personalise your Tesco Mobile experience**

| 

Use your online browsing behaviour as well as your in-store and online purchases (including Clubcard transactions where registered) to help us better understand you as a customer and provide you with personalised offers and services.

| 

Looking at your browsing behaviour and purchases allows us to personalise our offers and services for you.  This helps us meet your needs as a customer.

| 

Legitimate Interests  
  
Provide you with relevant marketing communications (including by mobile call, email, SMS, post or online advertising), relating to our products and services. 

As part of this, online advertising may be displayed on websites across the Tesco Group and on other organisations’ websites and online media channels. We may also measure the effectiveness of our marketing communications.

| 

We want to ensure that we provide you with marketing communications, including online advertising, that are relevant to your interests. To achieve this we also measure your responses to marketing communications relating to products and services we offer, which also means we can offer you products and services that better meet your needs as a customer.

| 

For most marketing communications we rely on your **consent** (which you can withdraw at any time) however there are situations in which it is in our **legitimate interests** to use your personal data in this way.  
  
You can change your marketing choices, both when you register with us, and at any time after that.  
  
You also have choices when it comes to online advertising.  We set out below your choices when it comes to cookies, and how you can control your online behavioural advertising preferences.  
  
**Contact and interact with you**

| 

Contact you about our Services, for example by phone, email, SMS or post or by responding to social media posts that you have directed at us.

| 

We want to serve you better as a customer so we use personal data to provide clarification or assistance in response to your communications.

| 

Contractual Necessity

Legitimate Interest  
  
Manage promotions and competitions you take part in

| 

We need to process your personal data so that we can manage the promotions and competitions you choose to enter.

| 

Consent  
  
Invite you to take part in and manage customer surveys, reviews and other market research activities carried out by the Tesco Group and by other organisations on our behalf.

| 

We carry out market research to improve our Services.  However, if we contact you about this, you do not have to take part in the activities. If you tell us that you do not want us to contact you for market research, we will respect this choice.  This will not affect your ability to use our Services.

| 

Consent

Legitimate Interest  
  
**Claims**

| 

In order to resolve legal claims or disputes involving you or us.

| 

For example disputes or legal engagement relating to our services

| 

Bringing or Defending Legal Claims  
  
**CCTV**

| 

To prevent and detect crime

| 

In order to protect our business, the local community, customers and colleagues.

| 

Legal Obligation

Legitimate Interests  
  
To help us to better understand you as a customer and to be able to provide you with services and marketing communications, including online advertising, that are relevant to your interests we also combine personal data we collect when you make purchases in-store using Clubcard with personal data collected from our Websites, Mobile Apps and other sources.

## Our Legitimate Interests in using your personal data

Where we have mentioned above our use of your personal data is based on our “legitimate interests”, these are:

  * to service our customers’ needs, including delivering our products and services;
  * to promote and market our products and services;
  * to service your account (such as enabling Clubcard coupons with Tesco Mobile), manage complaints and resolve any disputes;
  * to understand our customers including their patterns, behaviours as well as their likes and dislikes;
  * to protect and support our business, colleagues, customers and shareholders;
  * to prevent and detect anti-social behaviour, fraud and other crime;
  * to test and develop new products and services as well as improve existing ones.

## Sharing personal data within the Tesco Group including Tesco Ireland Limited

This section explains how and why we share personal data with other companies within the Tesco Group.

We may share the personal data we collect with other companies in the Tesco Group. For example, we share personal data with the following Tesco Group companies.

###  Tesco Clubcard 

Where you have registered and agreed, Tesco Mobile Ireland may share information with Clubcard (including information about purchases when you use your Clubcard) and information about your online behaviour. This helps us to improve our service and make our marketing communications more relevant to you. 

You can find more information about the way in which Clubcard use your data in their privacy and cookies policy.

### dunnhumby

dunnhumby, part of the Tesco Group, is also one of our main service providers. dunnhumby help us to use personal data to help improve our understanding of customers and personalise your customer experience. You can find out more about what dunnhumby do [here](https://www.dunnhumby.com/)

## Sharing personal data with Retail Partners and Service Providers

This section explains how and why we share personal data with Retail Partners and Service Providers. 

When we share personal data with these companies we require them to keep it safe, and they must not use your personal data for their own marketing purposes.

Retail Partners  |  We work with a number of Retail Partners who sell products through our Services   
---|---  
Service Providers  | 

Other communications service providers and network operators for provision of services such as switching, roaming and for the detection, identification and prevention of payment default, theft and fraud. Credit scoring and or automated decision making systems when assessing an application. Credit reference and or fraud prevention agencies. If we suspect that you have given us false information and we have reasonable grounds to do a further investigation. We may pass on your data to a third party if you fail to meet your contractual obligations.

We work with carefully selected Service Providers that carry out certain functions on our behalf. These include, for example, companies that help us with technology services, storing, combining and analysing data, processing payments, provide us with legal or other professional services as well as delivering orders. We only share personal data that enable our Service Providers to provide their services. 

Some of the Service Providers we work with operate online media channels, and they place relevant online advertising for our products and services, as well as those of our suppliers and our Retail Partners, on those online media channels on our behalf. For example, you may see an advert for our products and services as you use a particular social media site. 

Examples of our Service Providers include Facebook, Adobe, Dunnhumby and WorldPay.   
  
## Sharing personal data with other organisations

This section explains how and why we share personal data with other organisations. 

We may share personal data with other organisations in the following circumstances: 

  * Credit scoring and or automated decision making systems when assessing an application
  * Credit reference and or fraud prevention agencies
  * If we suspect a material breach of our terms and conditions and we have grounds to investigate further
  * Your mobile number (Calling line identity) will be visible when calling the emergency services. You can amend this for calls to other parties however are unable to mask your number when sending SMS or MMS messages.
  * if the law or a public authority says we must share the personal data or for the administration of justice or the prevention, detection, investigation of a serious offence.
  * if we need to share personal data in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (this includes providing personal data to others for the purposes of preventing fraud);
  * where we restructure, sell or transfer our business (or a part of it). For example in connection with a takeover or merger. 

##  How we protect personal data 

We know how important it is to protect and manage your personal data. This section sets out some of the measures we have in place: 

  * We apply physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personal data;
  * We protect the security of your information while it is being transmitted by encrypting it;
  * We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption to keep this data safe; 
  * We only authorise access to employees and trusted partners who need it to carry out their responsibilities;
  * We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we carry out penetration testing to identify ways to further strengthen security;
  * We will ask for proof of identity before we share your personal data with you; and
  * We will reveal only the last four digits of your payment card number when confirming an order.

Whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, it is important that you keep your login details and devices protected from unauthorised access. 

The personal data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by companies operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our service providers. If we do this we ensure that your privacy rights are respected in line with this Policy. The most common way we do this is to put in place a specific type of contract, a copy of this type of contract can be found [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm) or through an approved scheme such as the [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). 

##  How long we use personal data for 

We will not keep your personal data longer than we need to, how long this is depends on several factors, including: 

  * Why we collected it in the first place;
  * How old it is;
  * Whether there is a legal/regulatory reason for us to keep it; 
  * Whether we need it to protect you or us.

The Communications (Retention of Data) Act, 2011 provides the following retention periods to specific data generated by your activity on our network. 

Call and text data  | 

We will retain your voice call and text data records (e.g. date, time, duration) for up to six months in our customer care systems.

For legal purposes call and text usage will be kept for up to two years.

For inter-operator billing purposes such records are kept for up to 12 months

This retention will take place in a restricted access system and the data will not be used for commercial purposes.  
  
---|---  
Data usage records  | 

We will retain your data usage records (e.g. capacity usage) for up to six months in our customer care systems.

For legal purposes data usage will be kept for up to two years.

For inter-operator billing purposes such records are kept for up to 12 months

This retention will take place in a restricted access system and the data will not be used for commercial purposes.  
  
Bills and account statements  | 

We will retain these for six years plus the current year.

We will remove the call details element of your bill after six months.  
  
## Marketing and market research

This section explains the choices you have when it comes to receiving marketing communications and taking part in market research.

We will send you relevant offers and news about our products and services in a number of ways including by mobile call, email, SMS, post or online advertising but only if you have previously agreed to receive these marketing communications. When you purchase our products or services, or register with us we will ask if you would like to receive marketing communications, and you can change your marketing choices at any time online, over the phone or in writing at any time. 

Unregistered users will receive a welcome SMS to advise them of their marketing preference and how to update their preference.

In the event that you cease being a Tesco Mobile customer we may contact you for a period of 12 months following your departure for win-back or retention purposes. 

We also like to hear your views to help us to improve our Services, so we may contact you for market research purposes. You always have the choice about whether to take part in our market research.

## Cookies and similar technologies

We and our partners use cookies and similar technologies, such as tags and pixels (“Cookies”), to personalise and improve your customer experience as you use our Websites and Mobile Apps and to provide you with relevant online advertising. This section provides more information about Cookies, including how we use them and how you can exercise your choices about our use of Cookies.

## How we use Cookies

Cookies are small text files containing a unique identifier, which are stored on your computer or mobile device so that your device can be recognised when you are using a particular website or mobile app. They can be used only for the duration of your visit or they can be used to measure how you interact with services and content over time. Cookies help to provide important features and functionality on our Websites and Mobile Apps, and to improve your customer experience. 

When you consent to Cookies on our Services, these may be used to do the following:

Improve the way our Websites and Mobile Apps work | 

Cookies allow us to improve the way our Websites and Mobile Apps work so that we can personalise your experience and allow you to use many of their useful features.

For example, we use Cookies so we can remember your preferences and the contents of your shopping basket when you return to our Websites and Mobile Apps.  
  
---|---  
Improve the performance of our Websites and Mobile Apps | 

Cookies can help us to understand how our Websites and Mobile Apps are being used, for example, by telling us if you get an error messages as you browse.

These Cookies collect data that is mostly aggregated and anonymous.  
  
Deliver relevant online advertising, including via social media | 

We use Cookies to help us deliver online advertising that we believe is most relevant to you on our Websites, on other organisations’ websites and using social media. Cookies used for this purpose are often placed on our Websites by specialist organisations. 

Cookies used for this purpose are often placed on our Websites by organisations providing specialist services to us. These Cookies may collect information about your online behaviour, such as your IP address, the website you arrived from and information about your purchase history or the content of your shopping basket. This means that you may see our adverts on our Websites and on other organisations’ websites. You may also see adverts for other organisations on our Websites.

To help us to deliver online advertising that is relevant to you, we may also combine data we collect through Cookies in the browser of your desktop computer or other devices with other data that we have collected, for example your use of Clubcard and in-store purchases.   
  
Measuring the effectiveness of our marketing communications, including online advertising | 

Cookies can tell us if you have seen a specific advert, and how long it has been since you have seen it. This information allows us to measure the effectiveness of our online advertising campaigns and control the number of times you are shown an advert.

We also use Cookies to measure the effectiveness of our marketing communications, for example by telling us if you have opened a marketing email that we have sent you.  
  
## What types of cookies do we use?

We use the following categories of cookies:

  * **Session cookies** – These enable your web browser to remember which pages on our Site have already been visited and what actions have been taken in a session. Session cookies allow users to be recognized within a website so any page changes or item or data selection you do is remembered from page to page. The most common example of this functionality is the shopping cart feature of any e-commerce site. When you visit one page of a catalogue and select some items, the session cookie remembers your selection so your shopping cart will have the items you selected when you are ready to check out. Without session cookies, if you click CHECKOUT, the new page does not recognize your past activities on prior pages and your shopping cart will always be empty. Session cookies do not collect information from the user s computer.  Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
_dc_gtm_UA-78906422-1 | This cookie is associated with sites using Google Tag Manager to load other scripts and code into a page. Where it is used it may be regarded as Strictly Necessary as without it, other scripts may not function correctly. The end of the name is a unique number which is also an identifier for an associated Google Analytics account.  
ASP.NET_SessionId | General purpose platform session cookie, used by sites written with Microsoft .NET based technologies. Usually used to maintain an anonymised user session by the server.  
  * **Performance cookies** – 'Performance' cookies collect information about how you use our website e.g. which pages you visit, and if you experience any errors. These cookies don't collect any information that could identify you – all the information collected is anonymous and is only used to help us improve how our website works, understand what interests our users and measure how effective our advertising is.  Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
_gid | This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics. It appears to store and update a unique value for each page visited. Expires after 1 day.  
_ga | This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics - which is a significant update to Google's more commonly used analytics service. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier. It is included in each page request in a site and used to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for the sites analytics reports. By default it is set to expire after 2 years, although this is customisable by website owners.  
_gat_UA-78906422-1 | This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites. Expires after a few seconds.  
  * **Functional cookies** – These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For instance, a website may be able to provide you with local weather reports or traffic news by storing in a cookie the region in which you are currently located. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.  Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
lpTestCookiennnnnnnn | This cookie name is associated with the LivePerson chat software used to enable live chat on a website. It is a pattern type cookie which uses a unique identifier for each page. It appears to test whether or not the browser is set to accept first party cookies. This is a session cookie.  
LPVID | This cookie name is associated with software from LIvePerson, which enables website owners to add online chat functionality to communicate directly with visitors. This cookie is believed to be a unique visitor identifier. Expires after 2 years  
LPSID-nnnnnnnn | This is a pattern type cookie associated with software from LivePerson which enables online chat functionality with site visitors. This cookie appears to be a unique session identifier.  
LPSessionID | This domain is owned by LivePerson. The main business activity is: Online Chat/Customer Data   
lang | This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services. Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting.   
  * **Advertising cookies/Targeting Cookies** – These include targeting cookies, which record your visit to our Site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We use this information to make our Site and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose. We also use re-targeting cookies, which remember information about your use of our Site so that we can serve promotional and other targeted information to you on other websites. These cookies are used in combination to recognise a user who is returning to our Site or who is visiting another website. Using these cookies, publishers and advertisers can draw up a profile and personalise the content you see.  Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
__qca | This is a cookie usually associated with Quantcast, a digital advertising company. They provide website rankings, and the data they collect is also used for audience segmentation and targeted advertising.  

You can find more information about the specific, individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below. If you do not consent to the use of any of these cookies, please disable them following the instructions in this Cookie Policy so that cookies from this Site cannot be placed on your device.

## Third parties operating through our Websites and Mobile Apps 

Our key partners are listed below with information about the services they provide to us. This list is not exhaustive but it does include those partners with whom we have an established relationship and whose cookie technologies are most frequently deployed through our Services.

Measurement & Personalisation | To analyse how our services are used, including to test different content versions. This data may also be used to enable us to personalise our services and the marketing of our services. |  [Google](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en&gl=uk)  
---|---|---  
Product recommendations | To enrich your shopping experience by delivering personalised recommendations to you on some of our websites.  |   
Online marketing | To personalise Tesco Mobile adverts shown to you via Tesco Mobile and on other websites based on your interactions with Tesco Mobile. For example, by using data about your transactions with Tesco Mobile, what you have in your basket and the pages and products you look at. We may also use your Clubcard data to better personalise our marketing via our main data partner, Sociomantic (a subsidiary of dunnhumby, a Tesco company). |  [Google](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en&gl=uk) Quantserve Doubleclick Turn   
Social media | To market to you via social media platforms and to enable social sharing and engagement on our websites. These companies may use your data for their own purposes, including to profile and target you with other advertising. |  [Facebook](https://en-gb.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies) [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy) [AddtoAny](https://www.addtoany.com/privacy)  
Commenting Delivering ads for our Retail Partners | To power commenting on our websites (e.g. Tesco Real Food)   
To enable us to personalise and deliver online advertising on behalf of our Retail Partners.  |  [Google](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en&gl=uk)  
  
You can find more information about the third party cookies in use on our Site in the table below:

**Cookie Name**

| 

**Purpose / Description**

| 

**Third Party**  
  
---|---|---  
  
__cfduid

| 

This domain is owned by AddToAny. The main business activity is: Social Sharing Services and Tracking

| 

.addtoany.com  
  
uvc

| 

This domain is owned by AddToAny. The main business activity is: Social Sharing Services and Tracking  
  
id

| 

This domain is owned by Doubleclick (Google). The main business activity is: Doubleclick is Googles real time bidding advertising exchange

| 

.doubleclick.net  
  
datr

| 

This domain is owned by Facebook, which is the world's largest social networking service.  As a third party host provider, it mostly collects data on the interests of users via widgets such as the 'Like' button found on many websites.  This is used to serve targeted advertising to its users when logged into its services.  In 2014 it also started serving up behaviourally targeted advertising on other websites, similar to most dedicated online marketing companies. This cookie identifies the browser connecting to Facebook. It is not directly tied to individual Facebook the user. Facebook reports that it is used to help with security and suspicious login activity, especially around detection of bots trying to access the service.  Facebook also say the behavioural profile associated with each datr cookie is deleted after 10 days. This cookie is also read via Like and other Facebook buttons and tags placed on many different websites.

| 

.facebook.com  
  
fr

| 

This domain is owned by Facebook, which is the world's largest social networking service.  As a third party host provider, it mostly collects data on the interests of users via widgets such as the 'Like' button found on many websites.  This is used to serve targeted advertising to its users when logged into its services.  In 2014 it also started serving up behaviourally targeted advertising on other websites, similar to most dedicated online marketing companies. Contains browser and user unique ID combination, used for targeted advertising.  
  
lu

| 

This domain is owned by Facebook, which is the world's largest social networking service.  As a third party host provider, it mostly collects data on the interests of users via widgets such as the 'Like' button found on many websites.  This is used to serve targeted advertising to its users when logged into its services.  In 2014 it also started serving up behaviourally targeted advertising on other websites, similar to most dedicated online marketing companies. Used to manage the login process, remembers user on return visit if they choose to stay logged in.  
  
APISID

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear.

| 

.google.com  
  
SSID

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear.  
  
PREF

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear. This is a common Google cookie, used across several of their services. Stores user preference and can be used to personalise ads on google searches  
  
SID

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear. This cookie is used by Google in combination with HSID to verify a Google user account and most recent login time.  
  
SAPISID

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear.  
  
HSID

| 

This domain is owned by Google Inc. Although Google is primarily known as a search engine, the company provides a diverse range of products and services. Its main source of revenue however is advertising. Google tracks users extensively both through its own products and sites, and the numerous technologies embedded into many millions of websites around the world. It uses the data gathered from most of these services to profile the interests of web users and sell advertising space to organisations based on such interest profiles as well as aligning adverts to the content on the pages where its customer's adverts appear. Used by Google in combination with SID to verify Google user account and most recent login time  
  
d

| 

This domain is owned by Quantcast. The main business activity is: Market and Audience Segmentation, Targeted advertising services

| 

.quantserve.com  
  
mc

| 

This domain is owned by Quantcast. The main business activity is: Market and Audience Segmentation, Targeted advertising services  
  
uid

| 

This domain is owned by Turn. The main business activity is: Marketing and Data Management Platform provider

| 

.turn.com  
  
JSESSIONID

| 

Real time online advertising platform  
  
auth_token

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting. Twitter does not currently provide information on the use of specific cookies.

| 

.twitter.com  
  
twll

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting. Twitter does not currently provide information on the use of specific cookies.  
  
secure_session

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting. Twitter does not currently provide information on the use of specific cookies.  
  
guest_id

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting. Twitter does not currently provide information on the use of specific cookies.  
  
__utma

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting.  
  
personalization_id

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting.  
  
remember_checked

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting. Twitter does not currently provide information on the use of specific cookies.  
  
remember_checked_on

| 

This domain is owned by Twitter. The main business activity is: Social Networking Services.  Where twitter acts as a third party host, it collects data through a range of plug-ins and integrations that is primarily used for tracking and targeting.  
  
SID

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. This cookie is used by Google in combination with HSID to verify a Google user account and most recent login time.

| 

.youtube.com  
  
HSID

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. Used by Google in combination with SID to verify Google user account and most recent login time  
  
demographics

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. Most likely used for demographic profiling and targeting for advertising  
  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. This cookie is used as a unique identifier to track viewing of videos  
  
PREF

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. This is a common Google cookie, used across several of their services. Stores user preference, can be used to personalise ads on google searches  
  
APISID

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
GPS

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
SSID

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
LOGIN_INFO

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
YSC

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
SAPISID

| 

YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.  
  
##  Your choices when it comes to Cookies 

To benefit from all the functionalities of the Site, it is preferable that you accepts all cookies. However if you so wish, you can usually change your web browser’s settings to refuse new cookies, disable existing ones or simply let you know when new ones are sent to your device. 

##  Web browser cookies 

You can use your browser settings to accept or reject new Cookies and to delete existing Cookies. You can also set your browser to notify you each time new Cookies are placed on your computer or other device. You can find more detailed information about how you can manage Cookies through your browser’s help function. 

If you choose to disable some or all Cookies, you may not be able to make full use of our Websites. For example, you may not be able to add items to your shopping basket, proceed to checkout, or use any of our products and services that require you to sign in. 

You can also manage advertising related Cookies used on our Services by opting out through the Service Providers listed in the table above or by visiting the YourOnlineChoices website. Where we display personalised adverts on other organisations’ websites, the AdChoices icon will usually be displayed. Clicking on this icon will provide you with specific guidance on how to control your online advertising preferences. More information is available on the YourAdChoices website. 

##  Mobile Apps 

Cookies work differently on Mobile Apps as they are coded into the App itself and will use a unique identifier created by your mobile device for use for advertising activities. You can turn off or reset this advertising identifier through your mobile device’s privacy settings. 

However, please be aware that, if you refuse or disable cookies, some of the Site’s functionality may be lost. 

## Third party Cookies

With respect to cookies issued by third parties, only the third-party cookie issuer concerned is likely to read or change the items contained inside this cookie. Tesco has no control over the cookies third parties are likely to install. These third-party cookies are subject to the privacy statements of these third parties. To see their policy on personal data processing or to change the installation and storage settings of third-party cookies, the user is asked to contact these third parties:

Settings for audience measurement and statistics cookies:

  * Google Analytics
  * Adobe Analytics

Settings for advertising cookies and behavioural targeting:

  * AdRoll
  * TradeDoubler

Settings for social network cookies:

  * Facebook
  * Google +

In addition, disabling a cookie or category of cookie does not delete the cookie from your browser, you will need to do this yourself from within your browser.

## How do I disable cookies?

If you want to disable cookies you need to change your website browser settings to reject cookies. How to do this will depend on the browser you use and we provide further detail below on how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers:

### For Microsoft Internet Explorer:

  * Choose the menu “tools” then “Internet Options”
  * Click on the “privacy” tab
  * Select the setting the appropriate setting

### For Mozilla Firefox:

  * Choose the menu “tools” then “Options”
  * Click on the icon “privacy”
  * Find the menu “cookie” and select the relevant options

### For Safari

  * Choose Safari > Preferences, click Privacy, then do any of the following: Change which cookies and website data are accepted
  * Select a “Cookies and website data” option: Always block: Safari doesn't let any websites, third parties, or advertisers store cookies and other data on your Mac

## Children / Minors

Use of our Services and the associated processing of personal data as outlined is this policy, requires parental consent for persons aged 18 years or under. Without such consent you should not use our Services

## Subject access rights

You have the right to see the personal data we hold about you. This is called a Subject Access Request.

If you would like a copy of the personal data we hold about you, please write to:

Data Protection Officer,   
Tesco Mobile Ireland Limited  
Gresham House  
Marine Road  
Dun Laoghaire  
Co. Dublin 

You can also email us at [Subjectaccess.RequestTMI@tesco.com](mailto:Subjectaccess.RequestTMI@tesco.com)

. 

## Other data protection rights

In relation to your personal data, you also have the right to:

  1. **have inaccurate information corrected:**
    * **Summary of the right:**  
if you believe we hold inaccurate or missing information, please let us know and we will correct it. 
  2. **object to our use of it:**
    * **Summary of the right:**  

      * **general objection** \- We will then consider you objection to our use of your personal data. If on balance, your rights outweigh our interests in using your personal data, then we will at your request either restrict our use of it (see section 3 below) or delete it (see section 4 below).
      * **objection in relation to direct marketing** – If you make such an objection, we will stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes. 
  3. **restrict our use of it:**
    * **Summary of the right:**

There are several situations when you can restrict our use of your personal data, this includes (but is not limited to):

      * you have successfully made a general objection (listed in section 2 above).
      * you are challenging the accuracy of the personal data we hold.
      * we have used your personal data unlawfully, but you do not want us to delete it.
  4. **have us delete it:**
    * **Summary of the right:**

There are several situations when you can have us delete your personal data, this includes (but is not limited to):

      * we no longer need to keep your personal data;
      * you have successfully made a general objection (listed in section 2 above);
      * you have withdrawn your consent to us using your personal data (and we do not have any other grounds to use it);
      * we have unlawfully processed your personal data
  5. **have us transfer or “port” a copy of it:**
    * **Summary of the right:**

You have the right to obtain a copy of certain personal data once the data was:

      * • Provided to us by you on the basis of consent or to perform a contract
      * • The processing is carried out by automated means
      * you have withdrawn your consent to us using your personal data (and we do not have any other grounds to use it);

Such copy will be provided in a commonly used and machine-readable format. 

To action any of your rights we may require proof of identity or further information from you to help complete your request. We will aim to provide you with the outcome of your request in a timely fashion however in instances where the request is complex we may require additional time to compete however will communicate any delay and expected timelines to you as soon as possible.

  6. **6\. complain to the Data Protection Regulator**

We would like the chance to resolve any complaints you have, however you also have the right to complain to the ROI data protection regulator (the ODPC) about how we have used your personal data. Their website is <https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Contact-us/b/11.html>

**More Information on your Data Protection Rights**

The ODPC website <https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Guidance-Material-Menu-Page/m/219.htm> contains more detail on the data protection rights mentioned above.

If you would like to speak to us about these rights in more detail, see the “how to contact us” section below. 

## How to contact us

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use personal data please contact our Data Protection Officer. 

Phone: | 01 215 2000  
Email: [dataprotectionTMI@tesco.com](mailto:dataprotectionTMI@tesco.com)  
---|---  
Mail: | Data Protection Officer  
Tesco Mobile Ireland Limited   
Gresham House  
Marine Road  
Dun Laoghaire  
County Dublin   
  
This Policy was last updated on 08/06/2018.

Version 1.2
